#### Contact

Pearl River, NY nancychiocchi@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/nancy-chiocchi-380397a (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

ACLS

**BLS** 

**Nursing Education** 

#### Certifications

**BLS** 

**TNCC** 

**ACLS** 

**PALS** 

#### Honors-Awards

State-Wide Nurses Appreciation "Hero Among Us" Award

**Nursing Peer Mentor Award** 

Army Spirit of Nursing Award

Servant Leader in a Global Society Award

Speaker at Convocation

#### **Publications**

Biley, F. & Chiocchi, N. (2007). Nursing: A sacred, healing dance.

Gaffney, D., Barry, D. Chiocchi, N., & Theis, J. (2005). A disaster

Research fellowship (2004) from The New Jersey Commission on

Frank, I. (2006). More on the emergency response to the gulf coast

## Nancy Chiocchi

Emergency Department Clinical Nurse Educator at HackensackUMC Mountainside

Greater New York City Area

## Summary

Experienced clinical nurse with a demonstrated history of working in the higher education industry and hospital setting. Skilled in disease management, nursing education, nursing documentation, Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS), Pediatric Advanced Life Support (PALS), and emergency nursing. Strong education professional completing a Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) focused in Nursing from Seton Hall University.

## Experience

American Mobile Healthcare Travel Registered Nurse June 2018 - Present (2 years 2 months)

HackensackUMC Mountainside Emergency Department Clinical Nurse Educator July 2016 - May 2018 (1 year 11 months) Montclair, New Jersey

- Emergency Department (ED) Clinical Nurse Educator.
- Developed a nurse intern program for novice nurses using the Emergency Nurses Association (ENA) modules and incorporated high-fidelity simulation, case studies, research, field trips and shadowing into the learning experience prior to experience with preceptor.
- · Develop competency program.
- Provide in-service training based on changes in practice or hospital regulations.
- Provide evidenced-based support to clinical staff.
- Primary Nurse Planner for NJSNA/ ANCC Approved Provider Unit.
- Lead Sepsis Committee Team member.

New York University
Clinical Instructor
December 2006 - December 2016 (10 years 1 month)

#### New York. NY

- Clinical instructor on Medical-Surgical units at New York University Langone Medical Center, New York Presbyterian Hospital, New York Downtown Hospital, St. Vincent's Medical Center, Bellevue Hospital Center, Mt. Sinai Medical Center and Community Nursing clinical sites.
- Taught Nursing Assessment class.
- Taught evidenced-based practice in nursing skills lab, also using high fidelity simulation.
- Co-Course Coordinator for Fundamentals of Nursing, Adult Health Nursing and Therapeutic Interaction courses.
- Faculty representative for Undergraduate Nursing Student Organization (UNSO).

Saint Michael's Medical Center Clinical Educator June 2015 - July 2016 (1 year 2 months) Newark, NJ

- \* Nurse Educator for the emergency department, critical care units and the post open heart unit.
- Provide support to clinical staff both clinically and with research.
- Provide continuing education activities on topics such as, Mitigating Workplace Bullying, Care of the Stroke Patient Using a Multidisciplinary Approach and Emergency Severity Index.
- Provide in-service training based on changes in practice or hospital regulations, such as, Alarm Management and Patient Safety, and Sepsis Protocol.
- Primary Nurse Planner of the NJSNA Approved Provider program.
- Completed the NJSNA/ ANCC Approved Provider renewal application for continuing education activities.

Florham Park Surgery Center
Perioperative Registered Nurse (RN)
August 2014 - June 2015 (11 months)
Florham Park, New Jersey

- Perform preoperative assessment prior to patient scheduled surgery and on day of patient surgery.
- Perform postoperative care to patients and provide education to patients and their family members.
- Provide emotional support to patients and family members preoperatively and postoperatively.

• Provide nursing care using a holistic approach and with the nursing process.

Newark Beth Israel Medical Center Cardiac Care Unit (CCU)/ Intensive Care Unit (ICU) RN May 2013 - August 2014 (1 year 4 months) Newark, NJ

- Staff nurse on a cardiac care unit (CCU) and intensive care unit (ICU).
- Provide holistic care to patients and families with an interdisciplinary approach.
- Participate in complex care of patients that includes heart, lung and renal transplants and complex care for patients waiting for transplantation.

Jersey City Medical Center
Emergency Department (ED) RN
January 2010 - February 2014 (4 years 2 months)
Jersey City, NJ

- Staff nurse in the Emergency Department/ Trauma Center for adult and pediatric patients.
- Member of Violence Prevention Task Force.
- Facilitator of Bereavement Group.
- Nurse Educator for Alcohol and Drug Rehabilitation Program.
- Co-Founder of Support Group for New Nurses.
- Presenter at Nursing Ground Rounds and Nursing Orientation.

# American Mobile Health Care ED RN

January 2006 - April 2007 (1 year 4 months)

RN in various Emergency Departments in New Jersey

Staff Nurse in various Emergency Departments:

CentraState Medical Center and Newark Beth Israel Medical Center.

Seton Hall University College of Nursing Research Graduate Assistant September 2003 - December 2006 (3 years 4 months) South Orange, NJ

- \* Taught undergraduate nursing students in the skills lab.
- Tutored pathophysiology for undergraduate nursing students.
- Performed library searches and retrieved journal articles on various nursing topics.
- Assisted with the preparation of grant proposals.

· Proofread proposals and publication.

Mountainside Hospital ED RN

2004 - 2006 (2 years)

• Staff Nurse in the Emergency Department, including main, fast track and triage.

# Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA)

Mental Health Specialist October 2005 - October 2005 (1 month)

- Provided mental health services to the community of New Orleans, Louisiana in the Katrina relief effort.
- Provided client education on topics such as, disease management, medication compliance and stress management.
- Assisted clients in finding resources for housing and jobs, as well as access to government resources.

United States Court of Appeals
Wellness Coordinator
January 1997 - May 2002 (5 years 5 months)
New York, NY

- Designed and implemented health promotion program open to employees of the District Court and Court of Appeals, including Federal Judges.
- Provided initial health assessment to members joining fitness center.
- Taught exercise classes.

#### iVillage

Contributing Writer

April 1999 - January 2001 (1 year 10 months)

- Wrote health and fitness related articles for website.
- Answered reader fitness and health related questions on website.

## Education

Seton Hall University

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Nursing · (2006 - 2021)

Seton Hall University

Master of Science (MS), Acute Care Nurse Practitioner/ Forensic Nursing · (2003 - 2005)

## Seton Hall University

Bachelor of Science (BS), Nursing · (2002 - 2003)

## University of Toledo

Bachelor of Science (BS), Exercise Science/ Cardiac Rehabilitation and Wellness Specialist · (1989 - 1996)